Paul Pacurar

Career Summary

Paul is a communicative, extroverted person, who loves to share his knowledge with others. He has grown in multinational companies, getting in touch with people from all countries of the world, working on many technologies and getting in touch with many clients, sometimes travelling abroad for them. He has passion for JavaScript and React mostly, and he is open to learning NodeJS as well, but he tries to apply good design and code quality principles no matter the programming language. He's ambitious to get hired into the best companies or projects that align with his professional goals. He studied Automation and Computer Science at the Technical University of Cluj-Napoca, Romania and then worked as a developer since 2009.

Summary of Qualifications

Experienced In:

- JavaScript
- React
- TypeScript
- Redux

- Angular
- C#
- Visual Studio
- SCSS

- HTML
- Jenkins
- SQL
- Jira

- TDD
- Jest
- Teamcity

March 2021 – present

Languages

- Romanian (native speaker)
- English (advanced)

Career History

Globant - Jefferies, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Web UI Developer

react developer - building the website for a multinational fintech institution based in London. As
technologies, JavaScript and React are the main thing, with ag-grid and web sockets. My
responsibilities were the front end development of new features that enable users to import data
into this application from various sources (xls, csv..) right into the browser, style the data
according to customizable formulas and also develop new UI components that interact with the
existing functionality. All these components had persistent settings and react to data changes
automatically, in real time.

Globant - Nissan, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

Web UI Developer (react)

when Nissan launched a new electric SUV, they needed a very appealing interactive web page. We
worked on integrating this solution to existing websites, configurable for many countries and
languages, and implemented web pages that presented the internal and external features of the new
vehicle. The user could click on various elements in the browser and see animations and text
descriptions synchronized with visual transitions. Main technology was react with hooks.

USOURCE, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

July 2019 – August 2020

November 2020 – March 2021

Fullstack Developer (angular)

the client was an important player in the hospitality industry, acquired by Shiji group. Our solutions
were integrated with Booking, Expedia, Radisson hotels, Sabre Hospitality and others. Main
application was a portal for media management that allowed hotel administrators to upload and tag
pictures of their properties. I was involved mainly in adding UI features, but also fix bugs and
performance improvements of the existing codebase. Technologies used were AngularJS, Angular,
Typescript, C# and MS SQL Server.

QUBIZ, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

JavaScript React Developer

- react-native application similar to WhatsApp (improving performance, bug fixing, notifications)
- react developer for one of the largest clients in Europe, the Astrata group, that needed a new UI for
 their fleet management software. The application showed a map in the browser with every tracked
 vehicle and its details displayed in real time. I was involved in building the front-end, as a part of a
 small team, collaborating with our dutch colleagues from the backend. Technologies used: React,
 Typescript, MaterialUI, DevExpress, Jest, Team City and agile methodologies.

ZippyTech.io, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

October 2016 - May 2018

May 2019 - July 2019

JavaScript Developer

- maintenance and documentation of open source and partially comercial suite of reusable components for React library. Note: documentation involved creating playground web pages in react with the components could be tested with various parameters
- real estate management app built on top of the components built by the company

3DZ, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

August 2015 - September 2016

JavaScript Developer

- Expanding the front end of an angularJs application that transformed digital content from pdf to HTML5 with in the browser editing capabilities
- a great focus was to make the app consistent and all browsers and also on mobile devices
- worked on various animations to mimic native look and feel
- integrated videos and various playback controls

BisSoft, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

December 2013 - June 2015

Fullstack Developer

- ASP.NET MVC developer, under health insurance adjudication project. The project was a multi layer web application that facilitated computation taxes for medical services. The project was done using ASP.NET MVC, Oracle DB, Entity Framework and Kendo UI.
- Participated mainly on development of both backend and frontend
- Learned better JavaScript with Kendo Telerik tools
- Reverse engineered C++ code
- Configured Jenkins for CI
- Wrote Unit Tests with 100% coverage

Yonder TSS, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

September 2011 - December 2013

.NET Developer

- Fullstack developer for various projects, most from banking or eCommerce, involved in maintenance and adding new modules to ERP solutions
- Fix cross browser issues
- Expanding dynamic eCommerce solutions (login page, cart functionality, sitecore)
- participating in SCAMPI preparation as an internal auditor, for CMMI level 3, achieved successfully

Education

Universitatea Tehnica din Cluj-Napoca, Romania

October 2002 - July 2008

BS, Systems Engineering